BalramJha

9310746778 & 7011988627 balramjha88@gmail.com



CAREER OBJECTIVE

A result oriented military leader with over thirty years of leadership experiences in diverse fields of administration seeking a challenging responsibility to perform & deliver measurable growth to the organization that I am a part of.

PERSONAL DETAILS

Date of Birth: 08th February 1968

Languages: English, Hindi

Expert-level proficiency

CONTACT

Permanent and Correspondence address: H-2/27E&F, 1st floor, Mahavir Enclave, Dwarka sec-1, New Delhi-110045

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

- Administration Operations, security management, inventory, material and logistics management
- Armament, explosive and logistics training from Indian Air Force
- EOD & IED disposal trained
- Technical and administrative management skill Public relations
- Software knowledge in MS Office

WORK EXPERIENCE

SENIOR MANAGER

DB Secure Solution Pvt. Ltd., Gurgaon, Haryana | May 2019 - Jul 2019

- Managing all AMC of CCTV, fire fighting system and access control system from clients as, JBM, CBRE, CUSHMAN WAKEFIELD, COCA COLA, STRYKER and more
- Managing team for prompt service with zero tolerance service 24x7
- Assisting management to achieving high volume of business.

BRANCH HEAD

The Muthoot Finance Limited (NBFC) New Delhi | Aug. 2018 - Mar. 2019

- Supervised all transactions related to Gold loan
- Cash handling
- Dealing with insurance & gold coins with clients

HOUSE MANAGER

Chhattisgarh Bhawan (Govt. of Chhattisgarh), New Delhi | Apr. 2017 - June 2018

- Planning, controlling and supervising security arrangements
- Initiating E-tendering procedure for AMC of various service vendors Initiating purchase of items from GeM portal
- Supervising various services and infrastructure maintenance works Physical verification of all assets held on the inventory
- Hospitality of guests like honorable Chief Minister of Chhattisgarh, honorable Governor, Pramukh Lokayukta, Chief Secretary, honorable minister, bureaucrats and their families.

INVIGILATING SUPERVISOR

TCS | June 2016 - Mar. 2017

Conducted various online examinations with TCS

FIELD EXECUTIVE

Davinta Technologies Pvt Ltd | Aug 2014 – May 2016

a venture of Vattikuti foundation of USA in collaboration with RGVN (Rastriya Gramin Vikas Nidhi) and IDBI bank.

- Conducting field visits to remote areas of Assam as in Project UNNATI
- Co-ordinating with local SHG to assist rural people to get bank loans for their livelihood

SENIOR NON-COMMISSIONED OFFICER (JUNIOR WARRANT OFFICER MACP)

INDIAN AIR FORCE | June 1988 - June 2014

- Trained at Mechanical Training Institute Air Force Station, Tambaram, Chennai Worked as Aircraftman at Barmer Air Base on various air armament stores, armament administration and material management procedure
- Posted in technical team for production, support for quality check procedure, their maintenance, proper storage, supply and receipt of all explosive from country nodal base as well as from abroad held on the inventory of Indian Air Force
- Worked as key personnel holding the inventory at Pokhran Air Range Appointed as an Assistant to CEO at Allahabad (Western Air Command).

- Appointed as Warrant Officer in Charge of Station Armoury. Recipient of appreciation from Station Commander.
- Appointed as in charge of storage and accounting for all equipments and items at Air Force Station

EDUCATIONAL TRAINING

- Sikkim Manipal University, Gangtok
- MBA in Human Resource
- Attended from May 2009- April 2011
- Mechanical Training Institute, IAF
 Diploma in Mech. Engineering
- Attended from June 1988- Dec 1990

PERSONALITY TRAITS

- Adaptability to different situations
- Leadership skill & a good team player
- Problem solving ability
- Positive thinking